Guide to the Yale University Women's Organization Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale University Women's Organization records
1943-2006
RU 70
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6
(10 boxes)
The records consist of minutes, including minutes of the Newcomer's Club, newsletters, annual reports, program records, correspondence, and printed materials documenting the activities of the Yale University Women's Organization.
Yale University Women's Organization
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 40 (YRG 40), Records of Yale clubs, societies, and organizations.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Biographical / Historical
The Yale University Women's Organization was established in 1965. The organization is open to women members of the Yale community, including faculty, staff, wives of faculty and staff, and other women affiliated with the university. Its main activities include educational lectures, social activities, and a scholarship program.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of minutes, including minutes of the Newcomer's Club, newsletters, annual reports, program records, correspondence, and printed materials documenting the activities of the Yale University Women's Organization.
College teachers' spouses -- Social networks; College teachers -- Societies, etc.; Universities and colleges -- Employees -- Societies, etc.; Women -- Education (Higher); Women -- Societies and clubs; Yale Newcomer's Club; Yale University Women's Organization; Yale University -- Employees -- Societies, etc.; Yale University -- Faculty -- Societies, etc.; Yale University -- Societies, etc.
- Minutes, newsletters, and report, 1964-1987; Accession 1990-A-137
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2022
  - Newcomer's Club minutes
    - 1982 Jun 10 (Box 1)
    - 1982 Sep 9 (Box 1)
    - 1982 Oct 7 (Box 1)
    - 1982 Nov 4 (Box 1)
    - 1982 Dec 2 (Box 1)
    - 1983 Jan 13
    - 1983 Feb 3 (Box 1)
    - 1983 Mar 3 (Box 1)
    - 1983 Apr 7
    - 1983 May 19 (Box 1)
    - 1983 Jun 9 (Box 1)
    - 1983 Sep 8 (Box 1)
    - 1983 Oct 6 (Box 1)
    - 1983 Nov 3 (Box 1)
    - 1983 Dec 8 (Box 1)
    - 1984 Mar 1 (Box 1)
    - 1984 Apr 5 (Box 1)
    - 1984 May 17 (Box 1)
    - 1984 Jun 12 (Box 1)
    - 1984 Sep 20 (Box 1)
    - 1984 Nov 8 (Box 1)
    - 1984 Dec 6 (Box 1)
    - 1985 Mar 7 (Box 1)
    - 1985 Apr 11 (Box 1)
    - 1985 May 30 (Box 1)
    - 1985 Sep 5 (Box 1)
    - 1985 Oct 3 (Box 1)
    - 1985 Nov 7 (Box 1)
    - 1985 Dec 5 (Box 1)
    - 1986 Jun 26 (Box 1)
    - 1986 Sep 4 (Box 1)
    - 1986 Oct 23 (Box 1)
    - 1986 Dec 2 (Box 1)
    - 1987 Jan 8 (Box 1)
    - 1987 Jan 29 (Box 1)
    - 1987 Feb 26 (Box 1)
    - 1987 Mar 26 (Box 1)
    - 1987 Apr 21 (Box 1)
  - Newsletters
    - 1982-1983 (Box 1)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 1)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 1)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 1)
  - Annual Reports
    - 1982-1983 (Box 1)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 1)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 1)
  - Report to the Faculty Club, 1964 (Box 1)
- Records, 1965-1982; Accession 1992-A-050
  Open for research.
  - Constitution, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Annual reports, 1965-1979 (Box 1)
  - Minutes and reports, 1976-1983 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, newsletters, and reports, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Minutes and newsletters, 1974-1978 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, lists, minutes, and newsletters, 1966-1977 (Box 1)
  - Pamphlets on YUWO, 1974-1982 (Box 1)
  - Records of programs, 1976-1979 (Box 1)
  - Tour and programs, 1968-1977 (Box 1)
  - Brochures of tours, 1971-1977 (Box 2)
- Records documenting the creation of spousal identification cards, 1986-1988; Accession 2007-A-160
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2023
  - Correspondence and memos, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 2)
- Records, 1943-2006; Accession 2008-A-091
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2042
  - Constitutions and revisions
    - 1965-2000 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 3)
    - Constitution and by-laws, review rules of president and vice-president, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Constitutional review ground rules and background information, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - By-laws, financial statements, academic calendar, 2000-2004 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Connecticut tax status
    - YUWO tax status, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Recognition by Yale, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 8 - 9)
    - Federal tax exempt status, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - State of Connecticut sales tax exemption, 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - IRS - Connecticut property statement, 1988 May 20 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Policy manual
    - YUWO Basics: A Policy Manual, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Job descriptions for officers and board members
    - Job descriptions, 1996-2002 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Historian, Circa 2000 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - YUWO'a first year and early history
    - Yale Faculty Club, 1943-1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Faculty Clubs of MIT and Harvard, 1968, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Brochures, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Clippings, 1965-1994 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - History and background information, 1965-2001 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Minutes, reports, constitution, 1965-2000 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Newcomers - the early years
    - Clippings, brochure, 1966-1970 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Reports, financial statements, activities, 1990-1998 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Reports, minutes, notes, 1958-1973 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Invitations, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Gourmet Club cookbook, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Past presidents - Governing Boards, 1965-2000 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Board members, 1965-2000 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Annual membership lists, 1965-2004 (Box 1, Folder 29 - 30)
  - Board meetings
    - Board meeting agenda and minutes, financial statements, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Board minutes and reports, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Board meetings, 2000-2002 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Board minutes, 1970-1997 (Box 1, Folder 34 - 39)
    - Board minutes, 1997-2004 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Annual reports
    - 1983-2007 (Box 2, Folder 41 - 42)
    - Financial records, 1998-2001 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Budgets, 2000-2002 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Annual brochures
    - A Guide for New Members of the Faculty and Their Wives, Circa 1960 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - A Guide to Yale University, Circa 1960 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - The YUWO Yale Handbook, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Brochures
      - 1967-1980 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - Newcomers Club, 1972-1991 (Box 2, Folder 49 - 50)
      - YUWO and Newcomers, 1991-1997 (Box 2, Folder 51)
      - 1997-2008 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Newsletters, 1965-2007 (Box 2, Folder 53 - 60)
  - Correspondence
    - External (outside Yale), 1969, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Internal (within Yale), 1967-1985 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - YUWO (within YUWO membership), 1965, 1994, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Committee - ad hoc, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Special events, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Important letters, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Annual activities
    - Gourmet group, 1983-1999 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Activities, 1969-1993 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - YUWO archives, Undated (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - YUWO Basics: A Policy Manual, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Scholarship program
    - Scholarship committee annual report, 1998-2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - History, 1993-2005 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Scholarship statistic graph, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Scholarship recipients, 1972-2000 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Fall and spring study groups, 1967-1997, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 79 - 80)
  - Special projects
    - Oral history and video, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Information and Counseling Service for Women, 1971-1990 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Annual luncheon, 1965-2006 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Newspaper clippings and obituaries
    - Clippings, 1964-2002 (Box 3, Folder 88 - 89)
    - Annual luncheon clippings, 1978-2001 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Obituaries, 1969-2001 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - One Story, Many Voices
    - Video project, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 92 - 93)
    - Audiotape transcriptions, 2000-2002 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Photographs
    - Annual luncheon, 1993-2005 (Box 3, Folder 95 - 103)
    - Audio-visual meeting, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Board (YUWO), 1997 (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - Book Club, 1977, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Breakfast for Ann Childs, 1991 February 11 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - Bridge group, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Christmas party, 1991-2005 (Box 4, Folder 109 - 117)
    - Evening Gourmet, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 118)
    - Gourmet lunch, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 119)
    - Holiday Gala, 1992, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 120 - 121)
    - Lunch and Learn, 1999 feb 11 (Box 4, Folder 122)
    - Luncheon at Marty Sherman's for old and new board, 2004 June 14 (Box 4, Folder 123)
    - Luncheon for Anita Coken, 2000 March 20 (Box 4, Folder 124)
    - Luncheon with Tom Duffy, Music School Associate Dean, 2001 February (Box 4, Folder 125)
    - Meeting, 2002 May (Box 4, Folder 126)
    - Miscellaneous, Circa 1998-2003 (Box 4, Folder 127)
    - Negatives, 2001 February (Box 4, Folder 128)
    - One Story, Many Voices, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 129)
    - Past presidents, Circa 1990s (Box 4, Folder 130)
    - Pearl Jubilee, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 131 - 132)
    - Quilting group, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 133)
    - Scholarship winners, 1990, 1996, undated (Box 4, Folder 135)
    - Skiing, 1999, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 136)
    - Tea, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 137)
    - Tennis, 1993-1994, 2001, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 138)
    - Tours, 1993, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 139)
    - Trip to the vineyards, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 140)
    - Trips, 1996, 2001, undated (Box 4, Folder 141)
    - Unidentified, Undated (Box 4, Folder 142)
    - Wine and cheese, 1993-2006 (Box 4, Folder 143 - 151)
  - In Celebration of the Life of Margaret "Magee" Fenn, First Congregational Church, Branford, CT, 1992 December 14; videotape (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Meryl Drabkin
    - Brochures, 1975-1978, 1990-1995 (Box 6, Folder 152)
    - Correspondence, 1976, 1992-1994 (Box 6, Folder 153)
    - Minutes, membership lists, reports, fliers, speaker's c.v., activities, clippings, 1975-1978, 1993-1996 (Box 6, Folder 154 - 157)
    - Sixteen month calendar, 1975-1979 (Box 6, Folder 158)
  - Computer files (Box 7–9)
    Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.